<collection>
  <document PubMedID="25642278">
    <title>Quantitatively evaluating the effect of social barriers: a case-control study of family members' opposition and women's intention to use contraception in Pakistan.</title>
    <section type="BACKGROUND">
      <sentence>Uptake of family planning services in Pakistan has remained slow over the past decade despite a rapid increase in availability and awareness, indicating that social barriers may be preventing uptake.</sentence>
      <sentence>Social barriers such as opposition by family members have largely been studied qualitatively; there is a lack of quantitative evidence about the effect of different family members' opposition on women's intention to use contraceptives.</sentence>
      <sentence>The objective of this study was to quantitatively evaluate the effect of family members' opposition to family planning on intention to use contraception amongst poor women in Pakistan who have physical access to family planning services.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="METHODS">
      <sentence>An unmatched case control study (nested within a larger cohort study) was conducted in two public hospitals in Karachi, Pakistan.</sentence>
      <sentence>Univariable and multivariable logistic regression analyses were conducted to compare risk factors between women that were not intending to use any contraceptive methods in the future (cases) and women that were planning to use contraceptive methods (controls).</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="RESULTS">
      <sentence>248 cases and 496 controls were included in the study.</sentence>
      <sentence>Negative contraceptive intent was associated with no knowledge of contraception (AOR = 3.79 [2.43-5.90]; p &lt; 0.001), husband's opposition (AOR = 21.87 [13.21-36.21]; p &lt; 0.001) and mother-in-law's opposition (AOR = 4.06 [1.77-9.30]; p &lt; 0.001).</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSIONS">
      <sentence>This study is the first to quantitatively assess the effect of opposition by different family members on women's contraceptive intent in Pakistan.</sentence>
      <sentence>Our results indicate that of all family members, husband's opposition has the strongest effect on women's intention to use contraception, even when the women have knowledge of and physical access to family planning services.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642279">
    <title>Overcoming the fragility - X-ray computed micro-tomography elucidates brachiopod endoskeletons.</title>
    <section type="INTRODUCTION">
      <sentence>The calcareous shells of brachiopods offer a wealth of informative characters for taxonomic and phylogenetic investigations.</sentence>
      <sentence>In particular scanning electron microscopy (SEM) has been used for decades to visualise internal structures of the shell.</sentence>
      <sentence>However, to produce informative SEM data, brachiopod shells need to be opened after chemical removal of the soft tissue.</sentence>
      <sentence>This preparation occasionally damages the shell.</sentence>
      <sentence>Additionally, skeletal elements of taxonomic/systematic interest such as calcareous spicules which are loosely embedded in the lophophore and mantle connective tissue become disintegrated during the preparation process.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="RESULTS">
      <sentence>Using a nondestructive micro-computed tomography (μCT) approach, the entire fragile endoskeleton of brachiopods is documented for the first time.</sentence>
      <sentence>New insights on the structure and position of tissue-bound skeletal elements (spicules) are given as add ons to existing descriptions of brachiopod shell anatomy,thereby enhancing the quality and quantity of informative characters needed for both taxonomic and phylogenetic studies.</sentence>
      <sentence>Here, we present five modern, articulated brachiopods (Rectocalathis schemmgregoryi n.</sentence>
      <sentence>gen., n.</sentence>
      <sentence>sp., Eucalathis sp., Gryphus vitreus, Liothyrella neozelanica and Terebratulina retusa) that were X-rayed using a Phoenix Nanotom XS 180 NF.</sentence>
      <sentence>We provide links to download 3D models of these species, and additional five species with spicules can be accessed in the Supplemental Material.</sentence>
      <sentence>In total, 17 brachiopod genera covering all modern articulated subgroups and 2 inarticulated genera were X-rayed for morphological analysis.</sentence>
      <sentence>Rectocalathis schemmgregoryi n.</sentence>
      <sentence>gen., n. sp.</sentence>
      <sentence>is fully described.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSION">
      <sentence>Micro-CT is an excellent non-destructive tool for investigating calcified structures in the exo- and endoskeletons of brachiopods.</sentence>
      <sentence>With high quality images and interactive 3D models, this study provides a comprehensive description of the profound differences in shell anatomy, facilitates the detection of new delicate morphological characters of the endoskeleton and gives new insights into the body plan of modern brachiopods.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642280">
    <title>Water-air CO2 fluxes in the Tagus estuary plume (Portugal) during two distinct winter episodes.</title>
    <section type="BACKGROUND">
      <sentence>Estuarine plumes are frequently under strong influence of land-derived inputs of organic matter.</sentence>
      <sentence>These plumes have characteristic physical and chemical conditions, and their morphology and extent in the coastal area depends strongly on physical conditions such as river discharge, tides and wind action.</sentence>
      <sentence>In this work we investigate the physical dynamics of the Tagus estuary plume and the CO2 system response during two contrasting hydrological winter periods.</sentence>
      <sentence>A hydrodynamic model was used to simulate the circulation regime of the study area, thus providing relevant information on hydrodynamic processes controlling the plume.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="RESULTS">
      <sentence>Model simulations show that for the studied periods, the major cause of the plume variability (size and shape) was the interaction between Tagus River discharge and wind.</sentence>
      <sentence>The freshwater intrusion on Tagus shelf exerted considerable influence on biochemical dynamics, allowing identification of two regions: a high nutrient region enriched in CO2 inside the estuarine plume and another warmer region rich in phytoplankton in the outer plume.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSIONS">
      <sentence>The Tagus estuarine plume behaved as a weak source of CO2 to the atmosphere, with estimated fluxes of 3.5 ± 3.7 and 27.0 ± 3.8 mmol C m-2 d-1 for February 2004 and March 2001, respectively.
      </sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642281">
    <title>Phytochemical and pharmacological progress on the genus Syringa.</title>
    <section type="Abstract">
      <sentence>Genus Syringa, belonging to the Oleaceae family, consists of more than 40 plant species worldwide, of which 22 species, including 18 endemic species, are found in China.</sentence>
      <sentence>Most Syringa plants are used in making ornaments and traditional medicines, whereas some are employed for construction or economic use.</sentence>
      <sentence>Previous studies have shown that extracts of Syringa plants mainly contain iridoids, lignans, and phenylethanoids that have antitumor, antihypertensive, anti-oxidant, and anti-inflammatory activities.</sentence>
      <sentence>This study reviews phytochemical and pharmacological progress on Syringa in the recent 20 years and discusses the future research prospects to provide a reference in further promotion and application of the genus.</sentence>
      <sentence>Graphical AbstractPhytochemical and pharmacological progress on the genus Syringa.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
    <document PubMedID="25642282">
    <title>A feasibility study of 60 consecutive patients operated for unstable thoracic cage.</title>
    <section type="BACKGROUND">
      <sentence>About 10% of adult patients in high-energy trauma sustain multiple rib fractures.</sentence>
      <sentence>Some of these patients suffer from flail chest leading to respiratory insufficiency.</sentence>
      <sentence>During last years interest and results for operative treatment has improved.</sentence>
      <sentence>The literature today all show positive results for surgical versus conservative treatment, specifically with regard to time spent in mechanical ventilator, complication rates and length of hospital stay.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="METHODS">
      <sentence>Between September 2010 and July 2012, 60 patients with flail chest or multiple rib-fractures resulting in unstable thoracic cage were operated.</sentence>
      <sentence>16 women and 44 men with an age between 19-86 years (mean 57).</sentence>
      <sentence>We used modern fracture techniques with plates and intramedullary splint.</sentence>
      <sentence>Thoracotomy was performed and lung lacerations were debrided (11/60).</sentence>
      <sentence>Time spent in ventilator, complications and other adverse effects was studied.</sentence>
      <sentence>The operated cohort was compared to results from six previous years, when none was operated for that diagnose (153 patients).</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="RESULTS">
      <sentence>There is a significant correlation between Injury Severity Score (ISS) and time spent in ventilator both for patients operated and not operated (p&lt; 0,01).</sentence>
      <sentence>The mean time in ventilator was 9,01 days for not operated patients compared to 2,7 for the operated (p&lt;0,0001).</sentence>
      <sentence>No clear pneumonias were found.</sentence>
      <sentence>We had two deaths during the acute period.</sentence>
      <sentence>The infection rate was low.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSIONS">
      <sentence>Open reduction and internal fixation is a safe method to treat the unstable thoracic cage with multiple rib fractures and flail chest.</sentence>
      <sentence>Complication are few.</sentence>
      <sentence>The treatment time in mechanical ventilator is significant decreased.</sentence>
      <sentence>The operative treatment is probably cost effective and can be recommended.</sentence>
      <sentence>Knowledge in thoracic surgery and modern fracture surgery is needed.</sentence>
      <sentence>This is a therapeutic consecutive, level III, cohort study with historical controls.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642288">
    <title>The horror of wrong-site surgery continues: report of two cases in a regional trauma centre in Nigeria.</title>
    <section type="BACKGROUND">
      <sentence>Wrong- site surgeries are iatrogenic errors encountered in the course of surgical patient management.</sentence>
      <sentence>Despite the 'never do harm' pledge in the 'Hippocratic Oath' drafted in 5(th) century BC, man is after all human, with this limitation manifesting in the physician's art despite his best intention.</sentence>
      <sentence>Beyond the catastrophic consequences of wrong- site surgery on the patient and surgeon, and the opprobrium on the art of medicine, the incidents have come to be regarded as a quality-of-care indicator.</sentence>
      <sentence>Orthopaedic surgery is a specialty with a preponderance of this phenomenon and the attendant medico-legal issues relating to malpractice claims.</sentence>
      <sentence>Consequently the specialty had pioneered institutional initiatives at preventing these 'friendly-fires'.</sentence>
      <sentence>Awareness and implementation of these initiatives however remain low in many parts of the world, hampered by a culture of denial and shame.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CASE PRESENTATION">
      <sentence>This report presents two cases of wrong-site surgery following trauma from road-traffic accident.</sentence>
      <sentence>The first case was a closed reduction of the 'wrong' dislocated hip in the trauma/emergency unit under the care of senior residents, while the second case was attempted wrong-site surgery on the right leg in a patient with fracture of the left tibia, in conjunction with bilateral femoral fracture and right radio-ulnar fracture; by an experienced Chief Consultant Orthopaedic Surgeon operating elective list.</sentence>
      <sentence>Both are orthopaedic cases, each with some trauma to both lower extremeties.</sentence>
      <sentence>Neither of the cases was formally mentioned anywhere in clinical discourse in the hospital, much less a formal report or audit.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSION">
      <sentence>There was no formal, institutionalized process to prevent wrong-site surgery in the health institution and this could have been largely responsible for these incidents.</sentence>
      <sentence>An open, mandatory process of reporting such incidents for relevant audit and awareness is necessary, as a mechanism for prevention rather than blame or punishment.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
    <document PubMedID="25642289">
    <title>Surface-spreading technique of meiotic cells and immunodetection of synaptonemal complex proteins in teleostean fishes.</title>
    <section type="BACKGROUND">
      <sentence>Different moderrn methodologies are presently available to analyze meiotic chromosomes.</sentence>
      <sentence>These methods permit investigation of the behavior of chromosomes in the normal complement and of sex and B chromosomes, two special types of chromosomes that are associated with the A complement and are present in many organisms, including fishes.</sentence>
      <sentence>However, meiotic studies are still scarce in fishes, considering the wide number of species in this group..</sentence>
      <sentence>Here, we describe a new protocol for the visualization of the synaptonemal complex in spermatocytes and oocytes of fishes and to the sequential use of the technique with other procedures and techniques such as immunodetection of the synaptonemal complex protein with a specific antibody and co-detection of DNA sequences by FISH.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="RESULTS">
      <sentence>The meiotic surface-spreading protocol used in the present proposal worked well in representative species of four fish orders and was useful in obtaining good results even in small specimens.</sentence>
      <sentence>Fish-specific antibodies and commercial products worked similarly well to detect synaptonemal complex (SC) proteins.</sentence>
      <sentence>The sequential application of fluorescence in situ hybridization using specific probes showed clear signals associated with the SC structures identified by immunostaining.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSION">
      <sentence>Here, we provide a useful and applicable immunofluorescent protocol for the visualization of synaptonemal complex proteins in the meiotic cells of fishes in surface-spreading preparations.</sentence>
      <sentence>Furthermore, this technique allows for the sequential application of other cytogenetic procedures.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642290">
    <title>A prospective, randomized comparative study of monopolar transurethral resection of the prostate versus photoselective vaporization of the prostate with GreenLight 120-W laser, in prostates less than 80 cc.</title>
    <section type="OBJECTIVE">
      <sentence>In this study we aimed to compare photoselective vaporization (PVP) with the GreenLight 120-W Laser and monopolar transurethral resection as surgical treatments of prostates less than 80 cc in men with obstructive benign prostatic hyperplasia.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="METHODS">
      <sentence>From February 2009 to March 2012 we allocated 101 patients with a prostate glands of less than 80 cc; patients were randomly assigned for surgical treatment with monopolar transurethral resection of the prostate (TURP) (n = 62) or PVP (n = 39).</sentence>
      <sentence>Serum prostate specific antigen (PSA), International Prostate Symptom Score (IPSS), Sexual Health Inventory for Men (SHIM), maximum flow rate (Qmax) postmicturition residual (PMR), transrectal ultrasound volumes (TRUS), postvoid urine residual (PVR), complications, re-operations and hospitalization time were collected.</sentence>
      <sentence>The patients were seen in the follow up at 6, 12 and 24 months.</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="RESULTS">
      <sentence>Median age was 69 (56-87) years old in the TURP group and 67 (51-87) years old in the PVP group.</sentence>
      <sentence>Mean preoperative prostate volume was 55 cc (40-72) and 60 cc (41-75) cc in the TURP group versus the PVP group.</sentence>
      <sentence>There was no statistically difference in subjectively (IPSS, SHIM) and objectively (Qmax-PMR) parameters and postoperatively complication rates between the two groups (p &gt; 0.05).</sentence>
      <sentence>A significant difference was observed in the PVP group with a 2 (1-4) days hospital stay compared with 5 (3-9) days for the TURP group (p  &lt; 0.001).</sentence>
    </section>
    <section type="CONCLUSION">
      <sentence>Prostate PVP and TURP are effective surgical treatments for benign prostatic hyperplasia.</sentence>
      <sentence>Postoperative functional improvements were durable and equivalent in the two groups.</sentence>
      <sentence>The two techniques have a similar complication rate.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642291">
    <title>An update on enzalutamide in the treatment of prostate cancer.</title>
    <section type="Abstract">
      <sentence>Enzalutamide is an oral androgen receptor inhibitor that targets multiple steps in the androgen receptor signaling pathway.</sentence>
      <sentence>In the randomized phase III AFFIRM study, significant improvements in survival versus placebo were observed when enzalutamide was used as a treatment for patients with metastatic castration-resistant prostate cancer (mCRPC) following prior treatment with docetaxel.</sentence>
      <sentence>Additional benefits included significant delay in time to first skeletal-related event, and improvement in several measures of pain and health-related quality of life.</sentence>
      <sentence>Treatment effects were consistent across all prespecified subgroups.</sentence>
      <sentence>The phase III PREVAIL study evaluated enzalutamide versus placebo in patients with mCRPC who had not received chemotherapy.</sentence>
      <sentence>Enzalutamide significantly decreased the risk of radiographic progression and death.</sentence>
      <sentence>There were also significant improvements in all secondary and prespecified exploratory endpoints, including delayed initiation of chemotherapy, reduction in risk of first skeletal-related event and a high percentage of patients with objective response compared with placebo.</sentence>
      <sentence>Enzalutamide was also studied in hormone naïve patients (as monotherapy) in a small, open-label phase II study in patients with prostate cancer who were eligible for androgen-deprivation therapy.</sentence>
      <sentence>A prostate-specific antigen (PSA) response, defined as ⩾80% decline in PSA level from baseline at week 25, was achieved in 92.5% of patients.</sentence>
      <sentence>Long-term follow up is ongoing.</sentence>
      <sentence>Despite differences between these three trials, enzalutamide displayed a favorable safety profile in all three patient populations.</sentence>
      <sentence>Similar rates of adverse events between the enzalutamide and placebo groups were observed in AFFIRM and PREVAIL, with fatigue, diarrhea, back pain and hot flashes being more common with enzalutamide than with placebo.</sentence>
      <sentence>Hypertension was reported at a higher rate in the enzalutamide group than in the placebo group in PREVAIL.</sentence>
      <sentence>Breast-related disorders associated with enzalutamide treatment were also reported in the Monotherapy trial.</sentence>
      <sentence>Few seizures were reported in any trial.</sentence>
      <sentence>Enzalutamide is being studied in several early disease state populations.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642292">
    <title>The potential role of stem cells in the treatment of urinary incontinence.</title>
    <section type="Abstract">
      <sentence>Voiding dysfunction encompasses a wide range of urologic disorders including stress urinary incontinence and overactive bladder that have a detrimental impact on the quality of life of millions of men and women worldwide.</sentence>
      <sentence>In recent years, we have greatly expanded our understanding of the pathophysiology of these clinical conditions.</sentence>
      <sentence>However, current gold standard therapies often provide symptomatic relief without targeting the underlying etiology of disease development.</sentence>
      <sentence>Recently, the use of stem cells to halt disease progression and reverse underlying pathology has emerged as a promising method to restore normal voiding function.</sentence>
      <sentence>Stem cells are classically thought to aid in tissue repair via their ability for multilineage differentiation and self-renewal.</sentence>
      <sentence>They may also exert a therapeutic effect via the secretion of bioactive factors that direct other stem and progenitor cells to the area of injury, and that also possess antiapoptotic, antiscarring, neovascularization, and immunomodulatory properties.</sentence>
      <sentence>Local injections of mesenchymal, muscle-derived, and adipose-derived stem cells have all yielded successful outcomes in animal models of mechanical, nerve, or external urethral sphincter injury in stress urinary incontinence.</sentence>
      <sentence>Similarly, direct injection of mesenchymal and adipose-derived stem cells into the bladder in animal models of bladder overactivity have demonstrated efficacy.</sentence>
      <sentence>Early clinical trials using stem cells for the treatment of stress urinary incontinence in both male and female patients have also achieved promising functional results with minimal adverse effects.</sentence>
      <sentence>Although many challenges remain to be addressed prior to the clinical implementation of this technology, novel stem-cell-based therapies are an exciting potential therapy for voiding dysfunction.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
  <document PubMedID="25642293">
    <title>Avoiding and managing vascular injury during robotic-assisted radical prostatectomy.</title>
    <section type="Abstract">
      <sentence>There has been an increase in the number of urologic procedures performed robotically assisted; this is the case for radical prostatectomy.</sentence>
      <sentence>Currently, in the USA, 67% of prostatectomies are performed robotically assisted.</sentence>
      <sentence>With this increase in robotic urologic surgery it is clear that there are more surgeons in their learning curve, where most of the complications occur.</sentence>
      <sentence>Among the complications that can occur are vascular injuries.</sentence>
      <sentence>These can occur in the initial stages of surgery, such as in accessing the abdominal cavity, as well as in the intraoperative or postoperative setting.</sentence>
      <sentence>We present the most common vascular injuries in robot-assisted radical prostatectomy, as well as their management and prevention.</sentence>
      <sentence>We believe that it is of vital importance to be able to recognize these injuries so that they can be prevented.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
    <document PubMedID="25642293">
    <title>Avoiding and managing vascular injury during robotic-assisted radical prostatectomy.</title>
    <section type="Abstract">
      <sentence>There has been an increase in the number of urologic procedures performed robotically assisted; this is the case for radical prostatectomy.</sentence>
      <sentence>Currently, in the USA, 67% of prostatectomies are performed robotically assisted.</sentence>
      <sentence>With this increase in robotic urologic surgery it is clear that there are more surgeons in their learning curve, where most of the complications occur.</sentence>
      <sentence>Among the complications that can occur are vascular injuries.</sentence>
      <sentence>These can occur in the initial stages of surgery, such as in accessing the abdominal cavity, as well as in the intraoperative or postoperative setting.</sentence>
      <sentence>We present the most common vascular injuries in robot-assisted radical prostatectomy, as well as their management and prevention.</sentence>
      <sentence>We believe that it is of vital importance to be able to recognize these injuries so that they can be prevented.</sentence>
    </section>
  </document>
</collection>